<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Two Activities</string>
    <string name="passage_one">
        For a long time, Native American culture has been misunderstood and unappreciated by many non-native people. Years of Hollywood movies showed Native Americans as villains and clowns. Along with some old-fashioned history books, these films created a negative image of Native American culture. In recent years, however, a new generation of Native American activists and artists have worked to change that. They have brought a respectful and realistic portrayal of Native American culture to the larger society. One of those Native Americans is the artist Charlene Teters.\n\n
        One night during the 1989 college basketball season, Charlene Teters decided to go to a game. At the time, she was studying for a master\'s degree at the University of Illinois. She decided to take her two children to watch the home team play in the basketball game. They were shocked at a performance by the mascot of the team. The mascot was a student dressed in traditional Native American eagle feathers. They did a fake native dance. Teters, a Native American herself, was deeply offended and her children were hurt and embarrassed.\n\n
        Teters was born in 1952 and is a member of the Spokane tribe of Washington State. She had grown up near the Spokane tribal reservation. Her grandparents taught her about the traditional beliefs and culture of the Spokane tribe. Tribe members believed it was important to pass their traditional stories from one generation to the next. Her father was an artist, and he inspired her to choose art as a career. She had already completed her college studies in art and was in Illinois for further study.\n\n
        The mascot that Teters and her children saw at the game was called Chief Illiniwek. That was a name for a group of Native American tribes based in Illinois. By the time Teters arrived at the school, the fictional chief had been a symbol of the university\'s teams for generations. No Native American had ever played the part of the mascot and real native dances were not performed.\n\n
        Teters was outraged that a university would use a caricature of an ethnic group as a sports mascot. Later, she explained that in our culture, each eagle feather represents a powerful act of generosity toward the tribe. It is earned with great sacrifice, and only a great and powerful tribal elder or politician would be entitled to wear such a thing.\n\n
        Teters began to protest silently outside sports events at the university, holding a sign that said, “Indians are human beings. Some people reacted negatively by spitting on her and calling her names. Some called her at home and left nasty messages. She felt she and her children were in danger, and she almost gave up. But other Native Americans joined her, and members of other groups that faced prejudice gave their support. Many schools had (and still have) Native American mascots or sports teams named “Indians” or “Braves.” Teters\' actions on behalf of Native Americans led to similar protests all over the country.\n\n
        In 1991 Teters joined other activists to form a group to speak up for Native Americans. She became the vice president of this group, the National Coalition on Racism in Sports and the Media. The group\'s mission is based on several important principles. The members believe that the use of Native Americans as sports mascots and school symbols is racist. The members also believe that imitating traditional Native American dances, music, clothing, and customs is disrespectful. These practices promote negative images of Native Americans and their traditional culture, they say.\n\n
        The group is still fighting for these principles all over the country, and it has had some success. One success was at the University of Illinois, where Teters protested silently. In 2005 the National Collegiate Athletic Association made a rule against the schools that use disrespectful Native American nicknames. The NCAA said that these schools could not host any post-season games. This meant that the University of Illinois could not do so either.\n\n
        At first, the University of Illinois wanted to continue to use its long-time symbol. Officials of the university tried to change the rule but were not successful. In the end, the university said that it would no longer use the chief as a symbol of the school. Since then, some students have tried to bring back the traditional mascot but they have failed.\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="passage_two">
        JavaScript is a coding language used for building dynamic websites and applications. The first version was created by Brendan Eich, an American computer programmer and technology executive, when he worked at Netscape in 1995. Many interactive websites and games use this popular script programming language. However, is JavaScript right for kids, and should your child start with JavaScript when learning to code? \n\n
        While JavaScript is used a lot in web development, its applications are not limited to this. Programmers use JavaScript to control advanced devices and robots as well. Kids who learn JavaScript have a head start on careers with future technologies in addition to building websites.\n\n
        What is JavaScript?\n
JavaScript is a programming language that conforms to the ECMAScript specification and enables developers to create and construct complicated, dynamic web page features. It’s a scripting language, meaning that it’s interpreted at runtime by a browser or other software. \n\n
        Whenever a webpage updates content, displays animated graphics, shows interactive maps, and performs other similar tasks, JavaScript is often at the center of it. Put simply, JavaScript is most commonly used to add interactivity to webpages. Anytime you visit a webpage that requires user input, has embedded video clips, or displays animation, JavaScript was likely involved.\n\n
        Consider JavaScript the main layer of a standard web technology cake. The other two layers are CSS and HTML. Because JavaScript is such a huge part of web development, it’s one of the most commonly used languages by professional developers. According to a survey conducted by the State of JS, 97% out of 23,000 developers have a working knowledge of JavaScript.\n\n
        Initially, JavaScript was a scripting language designed to help validate information that users input into forms without slowing down loading times (this was back in the 1990’s when Internet speeds were already slow enough). With time, JavaScript evolved to become a full-blown programming language. Today, developers use JavaScript to create web and mobile applications that can process user actions without needing to load a new page. JavaScript can also be used to build Artificial Intelligence tools.\n\n
        While JavaScript does have uses outside of web development, its functions for websites are still the most common use for this language. For web development, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS interact with each other to create a website’s front-end design (how the website looks to visitors). They work together by sharing information to create style, content, and interactivity for projects.\n\n

    </string>
    <string name="passage_three">
        One of the most common reasons that our students enroll in our coding programs for kids is because they are interested in game development. And why not? The gaming industry as a whole was valued at more than 150 billion dollars in 2020, according to a report from Newzoo, and that number is only going to increase over time. Without a doubt, the gaming industry has viable job opportunities for teens looking to get into coding.\n\n
        But games can be coded in a ton of different programming languages, which can make it difficult to know which one to start with. \n\n
        With its easy-to-read syntax, a variety of useful code libraries and its use in a number of popular games, Python is a great starting point for coding a game.   \n\n
        Is Python Good for Game Development?\n
So, let’s get down to the heart of the subject!\n
        Is Python even any good for game development? For beginner game developers, Python is a great coding language to start with for a few reasons:\n\n
        1. Easy to understand syntax\n
2.Ability to reuse code\n
3. Easy to debug\n
        While large game studios use languages that offer more speed and allow for better graphics, Python has a lot going for it that makes it an especially useful language for game development. Python is very commonly used by large game studios for game prototyping, which means the original version of some of your favorite games may very well have been written in Python before getting re-made in a faster language. \n\n
        In addition, large games may supplement their codebase with Python for specific components of their game. Battlefield 2 uses Python for the implementation of scorekeeping and team balancing while Civilization 4 has its inner logic and AI written using Python.\n\n
        Interestingly, the same properties that make Python a great starting point for the pros are what make it such a great language for beginners taking their first steps into game-making. \n\n

    </string>
</resources>